Guide to the People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA) Research Files
People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA) Research Files
1980 - 2001
1980 2001
People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals
MC 00353
Clippings, tear sheets, reprints, offprints, reports, newsletters, copies of articles from magazines and newspapers, and other printed, typescript, or photocopied items compiled by People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA), from their earliest days through 2001. Among the subjects included are smuggling and poaching, genetic engineering, drug testing, pest control experimentation, alternatives to animal testing, xenografts, transplants, and military use of animals for wound experimentation.
People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA) was established in 1980 with offices in Norfolk, Virginia. The organization now extends throughout the world with affiliates in the United Kingdom, Germany, the Netherlands, India, Italy, Greece, and Australia. Since its establishment it has worked to effect major changes in the treatment of animals by bringing together members of the scientific, judicial, and legislative communities.
78 linear feet
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Gift of PETA
The collection is organized into nine series: 1. Anti-Animal Organizations,2. Pro-Animal Organizations,3. Progressive Organizations,4. Experimentation,5. Genetic Engineering,6. Pest Control,7. Confidential Subject Files,8. Subject Files,9. Other Files.
People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA) was established in 1980 with offices in Norfolk, Virginia, but now extends throughout the world with affiliates in the United Kingdom, Germany, the Netherlands, India, Italy, Greece, and Australia. Since its establishment it has worked through public education, cruelty investigations, research, animal rescue, legislation, special events, celebrity involvement, and protest campaigns to effect change in the treatment of animals.
Clippings, tear sheets, reprints, offprints, reports, newsletters, copies of articles from magazines and newspapers, and other printed, typescript, or photocopied items compiled by People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA), from their earliest days through 2001. The list of subjects in the file index includes smuggling and poaching, genetic engineering, drug testing, pest control experimentation, alternatives to animal testing, xenografts, transplants and military destruction and mutilation of animals for wound experimentation.
The collection has an extensive assembly of information about both "pro animal rights" organizations and about organizations that are regarded as antipathetic to the cause of animals.
People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals; People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals; Animal welfare; Animal Welfare and Rights; Animal rights; Animal rights movement; Animal genetic engineering; Alternative toxicity testing
- Anti-Animal Organizations, 11.5 linear feet
  - Aboriginal Trappers Federation of Canada (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ACIF (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service (ASCS) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alaska Outdoor Council (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alaska Reindeer Herders Association (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alliance for America (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Agri-Women (AAW) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Alligator Council (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Alligator Farmers Association (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Angus Association (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Animal Welfare Foundation (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American Association of Meat Processors (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Association of Zoological Parks and Aquariums (AAZPA) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Bison Association (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Boarding Kennels Association - empty file (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Dairy Association (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Ecological Union (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - American Egg Board (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - American Egg Producers Association (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - American Farm Bureau Federation (bad organization) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - American Feed Industry Association (AFIA) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - American Firearms Association (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - American Fishing Tackle Manufacturers Association (AFTMA) (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Forestry Association (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - American Fur Industry (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - American Fur Resources Foundation (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - American Greyhound Council (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - American Honey Producers Association (food) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - American Horse Council (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - American Horse Shows Association (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - American Hunting Rights Action Commission (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - American Kennel Club (correspondence, articles, policy, etc.—largish file) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - American Lamb Council (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - American Lamb Producers (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - American League of Anglers (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Meat Institute (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Meat Science Association (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Nat’l Cattlewomen, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - American Ostrich Association (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - American Paper Institute (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - American Petroleum Institute (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - American Pigeon Racing Union (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - American Professional Pet Distributors, Inc. (APPDI) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - American Quarter Horse Association (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - American Rabbit Breeders Association, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - American Red Cross (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - American Seafood Institute (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - American Sheep Industry Association (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - American Shooting Sports Council (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - American Simmental Association (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - American Society of Animal Science (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - American Veal Association (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) 3”; correspondence, reports, etc.) - folder 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) 3”; correspondence, reports, etc.) - folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) 3”; correspondence, reports, etc.) - folder 3 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) 3”; correspondence, reports, etc.) - folder 4 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Animal Blood Bank (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Animal Damage Control (correspondence, clippings, articles, etc.) 3” - 1 of 4 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Animal Damage Control (correspondence, clippings, articles, etc.) 3” - 2 of 4 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Animal Damage Control (correspondence, clippings, articles, etc.) 3” - 3 of 4 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Animal Damage Control (correspondence, clippings, articles, etc.) 3” - 4 of 4 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Animal Industry Foundation (much anti-animal activists literature) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Animal Lovers League (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Animal Welfare Caucus (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Animal Welfare Committee (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Animal Welfare Foundation (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Arizona Board of Veterinary Examiners (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Armadillos (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Army Corps of Engineers (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Association for Conservation Information (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Atlantic Coast Conservation Association (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Atlantic Salmon Federation (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Atlantic States Gay Rodeo Association (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Australian Mean and Livestock - empty file (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Bass Anglers Sportsman Society (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bats (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Birds - 1 of 4 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Birds - 2 of 4 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Birds - 3 of 4 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Birds - 4 of 4 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Cats - 1 of 5 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Cats - 2 of 5 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Cats - 3 of 5 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Cats - 4 of 5 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cats - 5 of 5 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cattle - 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cattle - 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Crustaceans (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Bats Dogs (Beagles, Greyhounds, etc.) - 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bats Dogs (Beagles, Greyhounds, etc.) - 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dogs—General - 1 of 8 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Dogs—General - 2 of 8 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Dogs—General - 3 of 8 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Dogs—General - 4 of 8 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Dogs—General - 5 of 8 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dogs—General - 6 of 8 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Dogs—General - 7 of 8 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dogs—General - 8 of 8 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Farm Animals - General - 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Farm Animals - General - 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Ferrets (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fish - 1 of 4 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Fish - 2 of 4 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fish - 3 of 4 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Fish - 4 of 4 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Frogs (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - General— 1 of 6 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - General— 2 of 6 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - General— 3 of 6 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - General— 4 of 6 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - General— 5 of 6 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - General— 6 of 6 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Beef Industry Council (1”: propaganda, opposition, BIC statements) - 1 of 3 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Beef Industry Council (1”: propaganda, opposition, BIC statements) - 2 of 3 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Beef Industry Council (1”: propaganda, opposition, BIC statements) - 3 of 3 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Beef Promotion and Research Board (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Boone and Crockett Club (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Bottom Line (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Bowhunters of America (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Boy Scouts of America (correspondence with PETA, before 1999) - 1 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Boy Scouts of America (correspondence with PETA, before 1999) - 2 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Boys Town (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - British Fur Trade Association (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Bureau of Land Management (policy and its effect upon animals) - 1 of 5 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bureau of Land Management (policy and its effect upon animals) - 2 of 5 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bureau of Land Management (policy and its effect upon animals) - 3 of 5 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Bureau of Land Management (policy and its effect upon animals) - 4 of 5 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Bureau of Land Management (policy and its effect upon animals) - 5 of 5 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - California Animal Owners Association (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - California Milk Advisory Board (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - California Milk Processor Board (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - California Poultry Industry Federation (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - California Wool Growers Association (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Californians for Balanced Wild-Life Management (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Campaign for Hunting (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Canadian Cattlemen’s Association (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Canadian Fur Institute (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Canadian Sealers Association (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Capital Research Center (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Casey Tibbs South Dakota Rodeo Center (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Cashmere Producers of America (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Cat Fanciers Association (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Catfish Institute (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Cattle Fax (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Center for Reproduction of Endangered Species (CRES) (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Center for the Defense of Free Enterprise (CDFE) (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Chocolate Manufacturer Association (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Christians Against Animal Rights (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Circus Fans Association of America (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Citizens Committee for the Right to Keep and Bear Arms (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Citizens for Individual Rights (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Cloverleaf Standardbred Owners Association (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Coalition for Animals in Research and Education (C.A.R.E.) (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Coalition of Arizona-New Mexico Counties for Stable Economic Growth (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Colorado Beef Council (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Commission for the Preservation of Wild Horses (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Commission on Dairy Industry Development (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Common Sense for Animals (CSA) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Sportsmen’s Caucus Foundation (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut Sportsmen’s Alliance (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Consumer Union (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Council for Ethical Hunting (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Countryside Movement (UK) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Dairy and Nutrition Council (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Dairy Bureau of Canada (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Dairy Coalition (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Dairy Producers of New Mexico (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Dairy Research Foundation (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Dallas Safari Club (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Dalmation Club of America (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Delaware Department of Agriculture (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Department of Natural Resources (DNR) (Bad organization) (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Driving for the Disabled (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Ducks Unlimited (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Egg Nutrition Center (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Emu Randiers Inc. (ERI) (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Entomological Society of America (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Exotic Wildlife Association (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Farm Animal Welfare Council (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Farm Bureau (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Father Flanagan’s Boys’ Home (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Feather and Down Association (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Federal Aviation Administration (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) (The FBI versus the “Monkeywrenchers” etc.) - 1 of 3 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) (The FBI versus the “Monkeywrenchers” etc.) - 2 of 3 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) (The FBI versus the “Monkeywrenchers” etc.) - 3 of 3 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Federal Trade Commission (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Federation for Fur Manufacturers and Dealers (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Feed the People (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Fertilizer Institute (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Fisherman’s Coalition (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Food Facts Coalition (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Food Inspection Service (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Food Marketing Institute (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Food Service and Packaging Institute (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Foundation for N. American Wild Sheep (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Friends of Rodeo (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Fur America (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Fur and Alligator Advisory Council (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Fur Commission USA (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Fur Council (clothing) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Fur Council of Canada (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Fur Education Council (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Fur Industry Mobilization Fund (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Fur Information Council of America (some protest information) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Fur Institute of Canada (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Fur Retailers Information Council (protests, trapping) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Fur Takers of America, Inc. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Future Farmers of America (letter from Gov. Bush about the death of a pig—1995) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Gamer Conservation International (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Gaming Advisory Council (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Global Guardian Trust (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Golden State Gay Rodeo Association/Bay Area Chapter (GSGRA/BAC) (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Gorilla Propagation Group (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Grand National Quail Club (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Greater Fur New York Association (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Grocery Manufacturers Association (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Gun Owners of America (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Health Insurance Association of America (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Heifer Project International (2”: propaganda and opposition) (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Homestead Rodeo Association (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Horse Racing Board (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Horseman’s Council of Illinois (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Hunter’s Advisory Commission (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Hunter’s for the Hungry (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Hunters Harvestshare (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Idaho Cattle Association (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Illinois Department of Transportation (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Indigenous Survival International (native hunting) (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Interagency Goat Management Team (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - International Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - International Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - International Atlantic Salmon Foundation (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - International Dairy Foods Association (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - International Fainting Goat Association (pet fad!) (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - International Fur Trade Federation (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - International Game Fish Association (IGFA) (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - International Livestock Centre for Africa (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - International Monetary Fund (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - International Professional Rodeo Association (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - International Shooter Development Fund (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - International Thoroughbred Breeders, Inc. (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - International Whaling Commission (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Interprofessional Committee of Foie Gras (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Iowa American Saddlebred Association (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Israeli Air Force (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Izaak Walton League of America (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Japanese Fisheries Agency (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Kidney Foundation of Massachusetts (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Lamb Cooperatives (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Livestock Conservation Institute (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Livestock Marketing Association (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Louisiana Foundation for Animal Use in Society (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Make-a-Wish Foundation (17 y/o wants to kill a Kodiak bear in Alaska, etc.) (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Maldon Institute (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Manitoba Trappers Association (clothing) (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Maryland Association of Agricultural Fairs and Shows (MAAFS) (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Maryland Bowhunters Society/Association (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Maryland Deer Hunters Association (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Maryland Egg Council (food) (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Maryland Greyhound Club (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Maryland Horsebreeders Association (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Maryland Jockey Club (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Maryland Racing Commission (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Maryland Saltwater Sportfisherman’s Association (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Maryland Sheep Breeders Association (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Maryland State Rifle and Pistol Association (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Maryland Waterman’s Association (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Massachusetts Committee to Save the Family Farm (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Masters of Foxhounds Association (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Max McGraw Wildlife Foundation (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Michigan Beef Industry Commission (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Michigan Sportsmen Against Hunger (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Michigan United Conservation Club (MUCC) (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Mid-Atlantic Rodeo Association (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Middle Atlantic Milk Marketing Agency (MAMMA) (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Middleburg Hunt (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Milk Advisory Board (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Milk Industry Foundation (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Minnesota Foundation for Responsible Animal Care (MFRAC) (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Minnesota Goat Association (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Minnesota Turkey Growers Association (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous - 1of 3 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous - 2 of 3 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous - 3 of 3 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous (Federal) (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Missouri Thoroughbred Racing Association (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Montana Beef Council (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Montana Department of Livestock (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Montana Industries Naturally Enticing (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Montana Stockgrower’s Association (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Nashville Council of Furriers (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - National 4-H Council (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - National Agricultural Chemicals Association (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - National American Elk Breeders Association (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - National Animal Interest Alliance (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - National Animal Protection Fund (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - National Bison Association (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - National Blue Bird Society (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - National Broiler Council (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - National Cattlemen’s Beef Association (NCBA) (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - National Consumers League (bad organization) (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - National Contract Growers Institute (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - National Contract Poultry Growers Association (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - National Dairy Board (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - National Dairy Council (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - National Dairy Goat Association (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - National Dairy Promotion and Research Board (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - National Farmers Union (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - National Fish and Wildlife Foundation (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - National Fisheries Institute (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - National Fishing Week Steering Committee (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - National Fluid Milk Processor Promotion Board (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - National Food Processors Association (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - National Geographic Magazine (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - National Grange (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - National Guard (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - National Hockey League (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - National Horse Show Association (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - National Hot Dog and Sausage Council (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - National Institute of Justice (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - National Livestock Ethics Council (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - National Marine Fisheries Service (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - National Milk Processors Promotion Board (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - National Milk Producers Federation 2” (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - National Park Service. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - National Pest Control Association (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - National Pork Board (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - National Pork Producers Council 2” (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - National Renderers Association (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA) - 1 of 10 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA) - 2 of 10 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA) - 3 of 10 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA) - 4 of 10 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA) - 5 of 10 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA) - 6 of 10 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA) - 7 of 10 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA) - 8 of 10 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA) - 9 of 10 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - National Rifle Association (NRA) - 10 of 10 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - National Seafood Promotion Council (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - National Shooting Sports Foundation (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - National Shooting Sports Foundation (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - National Smokers Alliance (bad organization) (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - National Trappers Association, Inc. (efforts to ban traps) (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - National Turkey Federation (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - National Wild Turkey Federation (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - National Wilderness Institute (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - National Wildlife Federation (along with items 1 through 3: 10” of information) - 1 of 5 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - National Wildlife Federation (along with items 1 through 3: 10” of information) - 2 of 5 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - National Wildlife Federation (along with items 1 through 3: 10” of information) - 3 of 5 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - National Wildlife Federation (along with items 1 through 3: 10” of information) - 4 of 5 (Box 15, Folder 3)